# **DAN EDWARDS**

danedwardscreative@gmail.com danedwardsdeveloper.com

Linkedin

#### FULL-STACK TYPESCRIPT DEVELOPER

#### **Professional Overview**

Full-stack web developer specialising in TypeScript and Node.js, using modern frameworks to produce clean, and maintainable code. Focussed on creating sites that are intuitive, responsive, and beautiful. Recognised for attention to detail, effective collaboration, and a drive for continuous improvement.

#### **Portfolio**

MetaCritic100 | GitHub | MERN web app with a stateless user authentication server for tracking top films.

Plant-Counter | GitHub | React Native iOS app for tracking how many plant foods you've eaten.

Array of Sunshine | GitHub | Web development blog made with React featuring book reviews and debugging articles.

Runway Rank | GitHub | (WIP). MERN web app that uses the Elo algorithm to rank Drag Race fashion photos.

Song Shop | Coming Soon page for a Next.js & Strapi marketplace for pop song recording rights.

### **Education**

Full-Stack Career Pathway | Codecademy
BMus (Hons) Cello Performance | Trinity College of Music | London

November 2023 - Present 2010 - 2014

## **Work Experience**

SEQ Writer, music producer & publisher | Freelance | 2022 - 2023

- Crafted compelling, keyword-optimised web content to add value, drive traffic and boost sales, mainly on the topics of music and technology. Excellent understanding of on-page SEO best practices
- Used notation software to craft best-selling arrangements for string quartet and orchestra.

Sub-principal cellist & senior music librarian | The Countess of Wessex's String Orchestra, British Army | 2015 - 2022

- Performing classical background music for investitures at Buckingham Palace, as well as other royal and state events.
- Managed a team of four as senior music librarian, demonstrating fantastic organisational skills and great teamwork.
- Collaborated closely with fellow musicians in an elite ensemble, ensuring precision and cohesion in rehearsals and performances.

#### **Core Skills**

- Semantic HTML 5
- Mobile-first & responsive design
- Bootstrap, Tailwind & jQuery
- Next.is
- Vitest, Supertest & Jest
- Headless WordPress & Strapi
- OpenAPI documentation

- CSS 3, Less, Sass & BEM
- Vue, Svelte & SvelteKit
- Accessible development
- Selenium & Puppeteer
- RESTful API developmentAgile & Scrum methodologies
- Express & Postman

- JavaScript ES6 & TypeScript
- React 18 & React Native
- Custom WordPress themes & child themes
- Node.js, NPM & PNPM
- Asynchronous programming
- PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite & MongoDB
- Stateless authentication servers

#### **Additional Skills**

- Version control, Git & GitHub
- End-to-end testing
- Command line tools
- WordPress optimisation
- Photoshop & Illustrator
- RESTful API development
- Vite & Webpack
- Chrome DevTools
- WooCommerce
- Canva & Figma

- Testing & test-driven development
- Deployment with Fly, Netlify & Vercel
- Docker & containerisation
- VS Code
- SEO & content writing